Register of the Pasternak Family Papers, 1877-2012
Hoover Institution Archives
- BORIS PASTERNAK FILE, 1912-1992 (Box 11-13)
  - Critical material, translations and other writings about Boris Pasternak (Box 13)
    - Pasternak, Evgenii, "Pered krasoi zemli," V mire knig, Printed copy, 1986 (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Pasternak, E. V. and Polivanov, K. M., "Pis'ma Borisa Pasternaka iz Marburga," Pis'mennost', Printed copy, 1990 (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - Pasternak, Josephine, draft of account of her meeting with Boris in Holograph, 1935 (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - Salys, Rimgaila
      - "Boris Pasternak on Leonid Pasternak and the Critics: Two Early Texts," RLJ, Printed excerpt, 1988 (Box-folder 13: 9)
      - "Boris Pasternak and his Father's Art," Oxford Slavonic Papers, Offprint, 1992 (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - Weidlé, Wladimir, "Boris Pasternak," Hochland, Printed copy, 1968 (Box-folder 13: 11)
    - Miscellany, Printed matter, 1943-1990 (Box-folder 13: 12-14)
  - Writings. Untitled essay re Petersburg and Moscow art circles, Holograph, 1912? (Box-folder 13: 15)
- Aleksandr PASTERNAK FILE, 1982 (Box 13)
  Biographical material, correspondence, and reviews of A Vanished Present, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Biographical material - Death (Box 13)
    - Letters of condolence, 1982 (Box-folder 13: 16)
    - Obituary, Typescript draft by Josephine Pasternak, 1982 (Box-folder 13: 17)
  - Correspondence - Pasternak, Rosalia, undated (Box-folder 13: 18)
  - Reviews of his memoir, A Vanished Present, Clippings, 1984 (Box-folder 13: 19)
- JOSEPHINE PASTERNAK FILE, 1916-1991 (Box 13-30)
  Biographical material; correspondence, including extensive correspondence with members of the Pasternak family and correspondence related to publications about Leonid Pasternak and the exhibition of his works; published and unpublished writings; diaries and interviews, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Biographical material (Box 13)
    - Autobiography, Holograph, 1929 (Box-folder 13: 20)
    - Biography, "Moskau-Berlin-London: Zu Besuch bei Boris Pasternaks Schwestern in Oxford," Typescript, undated (Box-folder 13: 21)
    - Interview, "Korotko o dvukh russkikh poetessakh, zhivushchikh v Oksforde," Typescript, undated (Box-folder 13: 22)
    - Subject file
      - Academic institutions
        - Official documents
          - Russian, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 13: 23)
          - German, 1924-1929 (Box-folder 13: 24-25)
        - Course listing, Ludwig Maximilians Universität München, Printed copies, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 13: 26)
      - Death, 1993
        - Clippings of obituaries (Box-folder 13: 27)
        - Funeral program (Box-folder 13: 28)
        - Letters of condolence (Box-folder 13: 29)
    - Visiting cards (Box-folder 13: 30)
  - Correspondence (Box 14)
    - Alphabetical
      - Incoming
        - Surname unknown
          - General, 1921-1935 (Box-folder 14: 1)
          - Mathilde, 1926-1936 (Box-folder 14: 2)
          - Nadia, 1920s-1930s? (Box-folder 14: 3)
          - Nina, 1924-1933 (Box-folder 14: 4)
          - Sonia, 1927-1930 (Box-folder 14: 5)
        - Adelson, Stella. See SUBJECT FILE
        - Aeby, Alphonse, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 14: 6)
        - All-India Fine Arts and Crafts Society, 1984 (Box-folder 14: 7)
        - Amnesty International, undated (Box-folder 14: 8)
        - Ashmolean Museum, Oxford. Includes correspondence with Ian Robatson, 1958-1990 (Box-folder 14: 9)
        - Bailan, Liu, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 10)
        - Barnes, Christopher, 1973-1990 (Box-folder 14: 11)
        - Bayerische Staatsgemaldesammlungen, Includes correspondence with Kurt Martin, 1962-1983 (Box-folder 14: 12)
        - Bayerische Vereinsbank, 1976 (Box-folder 14: 13)
        - Belikov, P., 1930-1932 (Box-folder 14: 14)
        - Berlin, Isaiah, 1953-1991 (Box-folder 14: 15)
        - Berman, Philip and Muriel, 1974-1988 (Box-folder 14: 16)
        - Bertelsmann GMBH, 1959 (Box-folder 14: 17)
        - Bibliothèque Nationale, Includes correspondence with Jacques Andrieu and S. Laffitte, 1958-1967 (Box-folder 14: 18)
        - Bowra, Maurice, 1944-1969 (Box-folder 14: 19)
        - Bradshaw, Jennifer, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 14: 20)
        - Brauer, David, 1977 (Box-folder 14: 21)
        - Breitmann, Michel, 1952-1959 (Box-folder 14: 22)
        - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), Includes transcript of "Critic's Forum," 1974. See also Cecil Parrott, 1962-1983 (Box-folder 14: 23)
        - British Medical Journal, 1983. Includes drafts of article by Josephine Pasternak and printed copy of issue, December 1983 (Box-folder 14: 24)
        - British Museum, 1976 (Box-folder 14: 25)
        - Buckman, David, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 14: 26)
        - Butler, W., 1977 (Box-folder 14: 27)
        - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC), 1980-1981 (Box-folder 14: 28)
        - Christian Action, 1961 (Box-folder 14: 29)
        - City Art Galleries (Sheffield England), 1978-1980 (Box-folder 14: 30)
        - City Art Gallery (Bristol England), 1959-1962 (Box-folder 14: 31)
        - City Museums and Art Gallery (Birmingham, England), 1985-1987 (Box-folder 14: 32)
        - Clark, Kenneth, 1971 (Box-folder 14: 33)
        - Collins Publishers, 1958 (Box-folder 14: 34)
        - Corinth, Thomas, 1958 (Box-folder 14: 35)
        - Craig, E. Gordon
          - Undated-1960 (Box-folder 14: 36)
          - 1961-1964 (Box-folder 14: 37)
        - Crankshaw, Richard, 1958 (Box-folder 14: 38)
        - Crawford Center for the Arts, University of St. Andrew's, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 14: 39)
        - Editions Gallimard, 1969 (Box-folder 14: 40)
        - Ettinger, Pavel, 1933 (Box-folder 14: 41)
        - Fatham, Andrew, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 42)
        - Feldman, Elihu, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 43)
        - Fleishman, Lazar
          - Undated-1983 (Box-folder 14: 44)
          - 1985-1987 (Box-folder 14: 45)
        - Fochtman, Vincent, 1927-1930 (Box-folder 14: 46)
        - Foot, David, 1963 (Box-folder 14: 47)
        - Franklin Library, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 48)
        - Gabrichevskii, Iurii, 1932-1936 (Box-folder 15: 1)
        - Gagarina, Ekaterina, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 15: 2)
        - Galerie Wolfgang Gurlitt, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 15: 3)
        - Gosudarstvennyi Ermitage, 1958 (Box-folder 15: 4)
        - Grabbe, Beatrice, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 15: 5)
        - Great Britain-USSR Association, Includes publications of the association, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 15: 6)
        - Gruening, Michael, 1984 (Box-folder 15: 7)
        - Hahn-Warburg, Lola, 1963-1985 (Box-folder 15: 8)
        - Hammer Galleries, 1959 (Box-folder 15: 9)
        - Hattingberg, Hans, 1928-1933 (Box-folder 15: 10)
        - Hildesheimer, A., 1955 (Box-folder 15: 11)
        - Hill, Sarah, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 15: 12)
        - Hirschl & Adler Galleries, Inc., 1983 (Box-folder 15: 13)
        - Hoare, Samuel, Sir, 1958 (Box-folder 15: 14)
        - Honig, Camille, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 15: 15)
        - Hoover Institution, Stanford University, 1986 (Box-folder 15: 16)
        - Hove Museum and Art Gallery (The Sussex Anglo-Russian Circle), 1961 (Box-folder 15: 17)
        - Hutchinson and Co. (Publishers) Ltd., 1963-1977 (Box-folder 15: 18)
        - Insel Verlag, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 15: 19)
        - International Martin Buber Society and Institute. See Camille Honig
        - Jackson, David, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 15: 20)
        - John Murray, Includes correspondence with Duncan McAra, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 15: 21)
        - Kaiser, Hans and Helen, 1983 (Box-folder 15: 22)
        - Kamishnikoff, Lev, 1959 (Box-folder 15: 23)
        - Kindler und Schiermeyer Verlag, 1959 (Box-folder 15: 24)
        - Kogan, A., 1938 (Box-folder 15: 25)
        - Konstantinovna, Lika, 1964 (Box-folder 15: 26)
        - Ladermann, Anatol, 1924-1933 (Box-folder 15: 27)
        - Levin, L., 1933 (Box-folder 15: 28)
        - Librairie Larousse, 1961 (Box-folder 15: 29)
        - Lifschits, Mathilde, 1959 (Box-folder 15: 30)
        - Literary Review. See Smith, Anne
        - Lobanov-Rostovsky, Nikita, See also SUBJECT FILE, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 15: 31)
        - MacKinnon, John, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 15: 32)
        - Macmillan Publishing Co., 1987. Includes correspondence with Marian Burleigh-Motley re biographical entry on Leonid Pasternak for Dictionary of Art (Box-folder 15: 33)
        - Mallac, Guy de, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 15: 34)
        - Maltzan Gallery Limited, Includes correspondence with Imre von Maltzahn, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 15: 35)
        - Mannsbach, F., 1924 1961 (Box-folder 15: 36)
        - Martinson, Helene, 1962-1978 (Box-folder 15: 37)
        - Mediterranean Review. See Camille Honig
        - Mock, Heinrich, 1962 (Box-folder 15: 38)
        - Monat, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 15: 39)
        - Murdoch, Iris, undated (Box-folder 15: 40)
        - Musée du XIXe Siècle, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 15: 41)
        - Museum of Modern Art, Oxford, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 15: 42)
        - Muzei A. N. Skriabina, 1989 (Box-folder 15: 43)
        - Napier, Charles, undated (Box-folder 15: 44)
        - Navrozov, Andrei, See also SUBJECT FILE, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 15: 45)
        - Nekrasov, Andre, 1988 (Box-folder 15: 46)
        - Neumann, Liuba, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 47)
        - Oestreich, Thorsten. See Verlag Atelier Im Bauernhaus
        - Ollington, Robin, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 15: 48)
        - Oxford Times, 1969 1978 (Box-folder 15: 49)
        - Oxford University Press, Ely House, 1958-1986 (Box-folder 15: 50)
        - Parrott, Cecil, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 16: 1)
        - Pasternak, Albrecht, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 16: 2)
        - Pasternak, Aleksandr. Also includes letters of Ina Pasternak (wife of Aleksandr)
          - Undated (Box-folder 16: 3)
          - 1921-1954 (Box-folder 16: 4)
          - 1967-1976 (Box-folder 16: 5)
        - Pasternak, Charles and Helen, 1936-1991 (Box-folder 16: 6)
        - Pasternak, Evgenii. Includes letters of Alena Pasternak (wife of Evgenii) and their children
          - 1920s-1966 (Box-folder 16: 7)
          - 1967-1980 (Box-folder 16: 8)
          - 1981-1989 (Box-folder 16: 9)
        - Pasternak, Evgeniia, 1965 (Box-folder 16: 10)
        - Pasternak, Leonid and Rosalia. Also includes letters from Lydia Pasternak and other family members
          - Undated (Box-folder 16: 11)
          - 1921-1922 (Box-folder 16: 12)
          - 1924 (Box-folder 16: 13)
          - 1925 (Box-folder 16: 14)
          - 1926 (Box-folder 16: 15)
          - 1927 (Box-folder 16: 16)
          - 1928 (Box-folder 16: 17)
          - 1929 (Box-folder 16: 18)
          - 1930-1931 (Box-folder 16: 19)
          - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 17: 1)
          - 1934 (Box-folder 17: 2)
          - 1935 (Box-folder 17: 3)
          - 1936 (Box-folder 17: 4)
          - 1937-1938 (Box-folder 17: 5)
        - Pasternak, Lydia, 1921-1985 (Box-folder 17: 6)
        - Pasternak, Osip, 1930-1935 (Box-folder 17: 7)
        - Patten, John, 1984 (Box-folder 17: 8)
        - Paul, H. K., 1959 (Box-folder 17: 9)
        - Paul Elek Limited, 1978 (Box-folder 17: 10)
        - Penguin Books, 1963 (Box-folder 17: 11)
        - Pensée russe. Includes correspondence with Zinaïda SHakhovskaia, 1976 (Box-folder 17: 12)
        - Perloff, Marjorie and Joseph, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 17: 13)
        - Phaidon Press Limited, 1978 (Box-folder 17: 14)
        - Pil'niak, Boris, 1922-1939 (Box-folder 17: 15)
        - Poizner, Mikhail, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 17: 16)
        - Polukhina, Valentina, Includes drafts of "Segodnia" and "Perepiska Borisa Pasternaka", 1980-1986 (Box-folder 17: 17)
        - Pomrock, M., 1960 (Box-folder 17: 18)
        - Proyart, Jacqueline de, 1959 (Box-folder 17: 19)
        - Pushkin Club. Includes correspondence with Mariia Kul'man, 1960 1974 (Box-folder 17: 20)
        - Quartet Books. Also see correspondence with Jennifer Bradshaw
          - General, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 17: 21)
          - Cole & Cole Solicitors, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 17: 22)
        - Réunion des Musées Nationaux, including Musée d'Orsay, 1982 (Box-folder 17: 23)
        - Rischen, Ruth, 1982 (Box-folder 17: 24)
        - Rosenfeld, Ernst, 1925-1989 (Box-folder 17: 25)
        - Ruge, Elizabeth. See S. Fischer Verlag
        - S. Fischer Verlag, 1958-1992 (Box-folder 17: 26)
        - Salys, Rimgaila, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 17: 27)
        - Save the Children Fund. See Lola Hahn-Warburg
        - Sender Freis Berlin, Abteilung Kontraste, 1983 (Box-folder 17: 28)
        - Schiller-Natsionalmuseum Deutsches Literaturarkhiv. Includes correspondence with Joachim Storck, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 17: 29)
        - Schnack, Ingeborg. See SUBJECT FILE (Box 18)
        - Schuster, Vera, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 18: 1)
        - Schweitzer, Maria and Renate, 1962-1979 (Box-folder 18: 2)
        - Scottish Field, 1978 (Box-folder 18: 3)
        - Shamir, Moshe, Includes typescript article, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 4)
        - Shtikh, Berta and Lev, 1929 (Box-folder 18: 5)
        - Silver Age Publishing, Includes correspondence with Gregory Poliak, 1985 (Box-folder 18: 6)
        - Smith, Anne, 1981-1989 (Box-folder 18: 7)
        - Society for Theatre Research, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 8)
        - Sotheby's, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 18: 9)
        - Soviet Union. Posol'stvo (Great Britain)
          - Bykov, Vladimir, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 18: 10)
          - Zamiatin, Leonid, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 18: 11)
        - Spat, Dunia and Gabriel, 1933-1959 (Box-folder 18: 12)
        - Spender, Stephen, 1959 (Box-folder 18: 13)
        - Städtische Galerie im Lenbachhaus, Includes correspondence with Armin Zweige, 1959-1982 (Box-folder 18: 14)
        - Struve, Gleb, 1958-1985 (Box-folder 18: 15)
        - Struve, Mary, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 18: 16)
        - Struve, Nikita. See writings Pamiati Pedro, correspondence
        - Studio, Includes draft of article about Leonid Pasternak by Josephine Pasternak, 1962 (Box-folder 18: 17)
        - Südwestfunk, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 18: 18)
        - Suhrkamp Verlag, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 18: 19)
        - Swet, Gershon, Includes clippings of his articles re Leonid Pasternak, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 18: 20)
        - Talbot Rice Art Center, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 18: 21)
        - Tate Gallery, 1958-1984 (Box-folder 18: 22)
        - Thomas, Don, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 23)
        - Totenberg, Jill, 1986 (Box-folder 18: 24)
        - University of Lancaster, 1978 (Box-folder 18: 25)
        - University of London, Courtauld Institute of Art and the Warburg Institute, 1974-1984 (Box-folder 18: 26)
        - University of Newcastle upon Tyne, 1979 (Box-folder 18: 27)
        - Vsesoiuznoe agentstvo po avtorskim pravam (VAAP), 1966-1981 (Box-folder 18: 28)
        - Verlag Atelier Im Bauernhaus. Includes drafts of publication agreement and German translation of beginning of Leonid Pasternak's Memoirs, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 18: 29)
        - Vicaire, E., 1957-1958 (Box-folder 18: 30)
        - Victoria and Albert Museum, 1958 (Box-folder 18: 31)
        - Waisman, F., 1948 (Box-folder 18: 32)
        - Wilma Wayne Fine Art, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 18: 33)
        - Wolff, Helen and Kurt, 1961-1983 (Box-folder 18: 34)
        - Woman's Journal, Pat Garrat, 1976 (Box-folder 18: 35)
        - Yale University Press, 1979 (Box-folder 18: 36)
        - Yorkshire Evening Press, 1962 (Box-folder 18: 37)
        - Zaguskin, J., 1936-1964 (Box-folder 18: 38)
        - Zamiatin, Leonid. See Soviet Union. Posol'stvo (Great Britain)
      - Outgoing
        - General, 1926-1986 (Box-folder 18: 39)
        - Conradi (?), 1986 (Box-folder 18: 40)
        - Levinson-Lessing (?), 1958 (Box-folder 18: 41)
        - Müller, M., 1986 (Box-folder 18: 42)
        - Pasternak, Boris, Holograph draft, 1956 (Box-folder 18: 43)
        - Ramsay, Helen, 1981 (Box-folder 18: 44)
        - Röthel (?), 1962 (Box-folder 18: 45)
        - Wildenstein (?), Typescript draft, 1957 (Box-folder 18: 46)
    - Business, 1962-1983 (Box-folder 18: 47)
    - Chronological (Box 19)
      - Undated (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - 1920s (Box-folder 19: 2)
      - 1930s (Box-folder 19: 3)
      - 1950s (Box-folder 19: 4)
      - 1960s (Box-folder 19: 5)
      - 1970s (Box-folder 19: 6)
      - 1980-1982 (Box-folder 19: 7)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 19: 8)
      - 1984-1989 (Box-folder 19: 9)
      - 1990s (Box-folder 19: 10)
    - Family, re distribution and use of Leonid Pasternak's works, 1985 (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - Diaries
    - 1950 (Box-folder 19: 12)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 19: 13)
    - 1952 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 20: 3)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - 1957 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - 1959 (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - 1960 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - 1961 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - 1962 (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - 1963 (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 21: 7)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 23: 9)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 24: 2)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Interviews
    - Phelan, Sarah, undated, "Interview with Josephine Pasternak," Typescript, February 11 (Box-folder 24: 5)
    - "Südwestfunk Wortwechsel," Typescript copy, undated (Box-folder 24: 6)
    - Österreichischer Rundfunk, Typescript copy, 1962 (Box-folder 24: 7)
    - Interviews and short articles given to Soviet and emigre publications, Clippings, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - Lectures - Pushkin Club, (?). See LEONID PASTERNAK FILE, Exhibits, Great Britain, 1958
  - Letters to the editor (Box-folder 24: 9)
  - Notebooks
    - Undated (Box-folder 24: 10)
    - 1922 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - Notes and fragments, Handwritten, undated (Box-folder 25: 3-4)
  - Writings
    - Published
      - General. Short articles and interviews, Clippings, 1963-1988 (Box-folder 25: 5)
      - "Probleme der Kriminalität," Monatsschrift für Kriminalpsychologie und Strafrechtsreform, Printed excerpt. Also includes correspondence, 1930 (Box-folder 25: 6)
      - "Ein Beitrag zur Lehre von den akustischen Intermittenzerscheinungen," Archiv für die gesamte Psychologie, Leipzig, Doctoral thesis, 1931
        - Printed copy (Box-folder 25: 7)
        - Photocopy (Box-folder 25: 8)
        - Proofs (Box-folder 25: 9)
      - "Patior,", 1964
        - Correspondence, The London Magazine, 1964 (Box-folder 25: 10)
        - Draft, Typescript, undated (Box-folder 25: 11)
        - Printed copies
          - The London Magazine, 1964 (Box-folder 25: 12)
          - Znamia, 1990 (Box-folder 25: 13)
      - Koordinaty, Published under the pseudonym of Ann Nay, 1978 (Box 26)
        - Correspondence
          - I. Baschkirzew Buchdruckerei, 1970-1978 (Box-folder 26: 1)
          - Petropolis-Verlag, 1937 (Box-folder 26: 2)
          - Victor Kamkin, 1973 (Box-folder 26: 3)
        - Drafts. Includes material published in Koordinaty and Pamiati Pedro, Typescript, undated (Box-folder 26: 4-9)
        - Printed copy (Box-folder 26: 10)
        - Miscellany (Box-folder 26: 11)
      - Pamiati Pedro, 1981
        - Correspondence
          - General, Includes business correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 26: 12)
          - Struve, Nikita, 1979-1991 (Box-folder 26: 13)
        - Printed copy, 1981 (Box-folder 26: 14)
        - Reviews, 1981 (Box-folder 26: 15)
      - "Ich bestand darauf, Blutvergiessen zu vermeiden: Erinnerungen an Alexander Kerenski," Der Monat, 1982 July (Box-folder 26: 16)
      - "Posledniia vstrecha s bratom," Sovetskaia kul'tura, Printed copy, 1989 (Box-folder 26: 17)
      - "Pis'mo sestry," Pravda, Printed copy, 1990 February (Box-folder 26: 18)
    - Unpublished (Box 27)
      - Poetry
        - Correspondence with publishers, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 27: 1)
        - Drafts
          - Handwritten, undated (Box-folder 27: 2)
          - Typescript, undated
            - General (Box-folder 27: 3)
            - 1957-1978 (Box-folder 27: 4)
        - Translations of Josephine Pasternak's poetry into Chinese by Liu Bai Lan, Calligraphy, 1982 (Box-folder 27: 5)
      - Prose
        - Case of "The White Rose," See SUBJECT FILE, 1953
        - "Heather and Broom," Typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 27: 6)
      - Reviews
        - Kerensky, Alexander, The Kerensky Memoirs, 1966
          - Typescript draft (Box-folder 27: 7)
          - Correspondence
            - Journal of European Studies, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 8)
            - The Literary Review, 1984 (Box-folder 27: 9)
        - Edwards, Anne, Sonia, the Life of Countess Tolstoy, 1981. Typescript draft. Includes correspondence with The Literary Review (Box-folder 27: 10)
      - Scholarly work. "Indefinability"
        - Working material
          - Clippings, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 27: 11)
          - Excerpts and tearsheets from scientific journals, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 27: 12)
        - Correspondence
          - General, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 27: 13)
          - Harvester Press Ltd., 1977-1980 (Box-folder 27: 14)
          - Oxford Polytechnic Press, Includes synopsis, 1984 (Box-folder 27: 15)
          - Petersen, Arne, 1977-1988 (Box-folder 27: 16)
          - Popper, Karl, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 17)
        - Drafts. Typescript (Box 28)
          - General. Includes handwritten miscellany, undated (Box-folder 28: 1-6)
          - Corrected by Arne Petersen (Box-folder 28: 7-8)
          - Corrected by Arne Petersen (Box-folder 29: 1-7)
          - Abridged second version (Box-folder 29: 8)
          - Summary (Box-folder 30: 1)
          - Content list (Box-folder 30: 2)
          - Synopsis (Box-folder 30: 3)
- LYDIA PASTERNAK-SLATER FILE, 1928-1989 (Box 30)
  Biographical material, correspondence and writings, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Biographical material (Box 30)
    - Obituaries, 1989 (Box-folder 30: 4)
    - Poster announcing poetry reading, undated (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Correspondence
    - Ernst(?), 1983 (Box-folder 30: 6)
    - Freidenberg, Ol'ga, 1945 (Box-folder 30: 7)
    - Mil'kovich, Mikhail, 1984 (Box-folder 30: 8)
    - Pasternak, Aleksandr, 1981 (Box-folder 30: 9)
    - Pasternak, Evgenii, 1967-1986 (Box-folder 30: 10)
    - Pasternak, Josephine, Includes poem, undated (Box-folder 30: 11)
    - Pasternak, Leonid and Rosalia, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 30: 12)
    - Raleigh, Marsha, 1982 (Box-folder 30: 13)
  - Writing. "Less than an Hour," Mediterranean Review, Photocopy, 1970 (Box-folder 30: 14)
  - Review of her Poems of Boris Pasternak, Orbis, Spring 1984 (Box-folder 30: 15)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1921-1990 (Box 30-34)
  Correspondence, writings and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General. Case of "The White Rose." Includes material about Kurt Huber and Alexander Schmorell. See also PHOTOGRAPHS. (Box 30)
    - Correspondence of Josephine Pasternak, 1948-1972
      - General (Box-folder 30: 16)
      - Huber family (Box-folder 30: 17)
    - Printed matter (Box-folder 30: 18)
    - Writings. Drafts and typescript of article prepared by Josephine Pasternak (Box-folder 30: 19)
  - Adelson, Stella
    - Correspondence addressed to Josephine, Lydia and other members of the Pasternak family
      - Undated
        - General (Box-folder 30: 20-21)
        - Fragments (Box-folder 30: 22)
      - 1921
        - January-August (Box-folder 30: 23)